# Alena Bushuyeva

11009 Alterra Parkway Austin, TX 78758 alena.bushuyeva@gmail.com (737) 222-8898

I am a digital designer and specialize in user experience design (competitor and customer analysis, user research, prototyping, and wireframing) and graphical UI design (visual design).

Before design, I had 6+ years of experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining restaurants), NGO (a leading member of organizing committee of European Chess Championship), executive assistantship @ Experience Experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining restaurants), NGO (a leading member of organizing committee of European Chess Championship), executive assistantship @ Experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining restaurants), NGO (a leading member of organizing committee of European Chess Championship), executive assistantship @ Experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining restaurants), NGO (a leading member of organizing committee of European Chess Championship), executive assistantship @ Experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining restaurants), NGO (a leading member of organizing committee of European Chess Championship), executive assistantship @ Experience in hospitality (helped to launch 2 fine dining helped to launch 2 fine dining helpe

#### **Design Projects**

#### The Independent, Real Estate

I created a landing page for an architectural project, an upscale resident house. My task was to define a unique value proposition, research the property and industry, conduct and provide a high fidelity prototype and interaction design for a website that would hold an upscale spirit of the real estate and architectural studio.

#### **Austin Design Conference, Event**

I designed a website for a design conference held in Austin, Texas. The primary intent was to drive awareness about the event and provide a way to sign up for it.

#### **Audible**, Consumer application

I conducted a redesign of the web and mobile applications for Audible for two primary use cases: searching for a specific audiobook and discovering the next audiobook to listen to.

#### Koenigsegg, Automobile Industry

Redesign of a website for a supercar manufacturer, modernizing the look of a digital experience to comply with brand qualities.

#### **Professional Experience**

# **Uprock Design Studio**

UX Design Intern Mar 2020—present

I participated in UI and UX design's full lifecycle, from conducting user research and competitive analysis and data synthesis to providing rapid prototyping deliverables and high-fidelity prototypes and specifications of web and mobile apps to the front-end development team following agile principles.

I worked on 5 projects, collaborating and receiving feedback from the studio's art directors.

Tools I used: Axure, Balsamiq, Figma, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Xd, Miro, InVision, Webflow, Jira, Confluence, Salesforce.

#### **David Yurman**

#### **Sales Representative**

Jul 2019—Aug 2020

My contribution as a brand ambassador and men's line representative led to achieving 215% over the yearly

sales goal for the men's department and achieving a personal sales goal (116%) within the first 6 months of employment.

I worked on providing exceptional customer service (see <u>customer reviews</u>) and identified customer needs, resulting in a competitive personal sales goal. I managed the outreach to the customers, achieving 45% of the repeat customer rate by building a loyal clientele.

#### **Neiman Marcus**

# **Sales Representative**

Oct 2018—Jul 2019

I developed and implemented a company's business strategy, worked on an understanding of the customer needs, creating a welcoming environment, and providing styling expertise to the guests, resulting in gross sales of 130% and being in the top 10 best sellers in the store over the time of employment.

I focused on developing long-term relationships with the customers, managing timely customer outreach, produced social media posts and 17 videos on styling, achieving 22% of returning customers using customer management software.

I represented the company on special events, such as Mack, Jack & McConaughey fundraiser, reaching 350% of the merchandise sales goal.

# Exp(capital)

**Executive assistant** 

May 2017—Sep 2018

Administrative and paperwork duties, office supply procurements, a full cycle of travel arrangements, managing office budget, and reporting in a fast-paced environment. HR and recruiting activities for Minsk/Limassol offices for Exp(capital) and sister companies (Capital.com, Banuba Development)

Design associate

Jan 2018—Sept 2018

Designed marketing and internal communication materials

#### **Belarus Chess Federation**

**Executive Assistant** 

Oct 2018—Jul 2019

Member of the Organizing Committee of the European Individual Chess Championship'17, Curator of "Chess in Schools" national project, Member of the Organizing Committee of the European Rapid and Blitz Championship in Belarus.

Design associate

Aug 2015—Mar 2017

Developed marketing materials for chess events (logo, brochures, newsletters, infographics, presentations).

# **Education**

# **Minsk State Linguistics University**

Bachelor of Arts Interpreter's Department 2011—2016

#### **Belarus Academy of Arts**

Associate of Arts Fine Arts 2003—2007